<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Diary on 📓 Notes</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/</link><description>Recent content in Diary on 📓 Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://notes.mpri.me/diary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Just Build</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-07-05-build/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-07-05-build/</guid><description>For the last 6 months, the prime directive has been to explore. To boldly go where I&amp;rsquo;ve never been before.
I&amp;rsquo;ve chased all sorts of opportunities and ideas while fighting back the instincts telling me that such projects are dead ends, not feasible long term, not sustainable.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of fun overall, and now that I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to suppress my inner voices of doubt, it is even more rewarding and enjoyable.</description></item><item><title>6 Months Free-Wheeling</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-06-01-free-wheeling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-06-01-free-wheeling/</guid><description>The roller coaster of emotions has smoothed significantly. Fear and anxiety have given way to joy and optimism. I’m feeling grateful every day about the general state of affair and almost never regretting my choices or use of time.
Work opportunities have been coming from all direction. And sharing my thoughts/ideas/projects with others consistently produces good feedback. Both factors contribute to silencing the voices of doubt that were annoying me in the previous months.</description></item><item><title>March Madness</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-04-01-march-madness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-04-01-march-madness/</guid><description>The month of march begun with a feeling of being lost. As more and more opportunities, projects, ideas started to materialize I found myself burning a lot of mental cycles thinking about time management. Questions such as:
How should I spend time? Is this thing I&amp;rsquo;m doing a good use of my time? Am I wasting my time? &amp;hellip; The worst part of this is getting distracted by these questions and doubts.</description></item><item><title>Clean Desk</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-02-25-clean-desk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-02-25-clean-desk/</guid><description>The first 6 weeks of 2021 have been a little rough. I was spinning my wheels, I felt I was not accomplishing anything.
The last couple of weeks have been great.
M. mentioned how he cleans his desk when working on a particular thing. My physical desk is always clean. But my virtual one wasn&amp;rsquo;t. I was used to working with everything open: multiple messaging apps, multiple browsers with multiple tabs, multiple note-taking and TODO lists, &amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>2021: The Plan</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-01-01-the-plan-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-01-01-the-plan-2021/</guid><description>Forget About Money There&amp;rsquo;s no need to try to monetize your time or your projects.
Worrying about money will only distract you and interfere with decision making.
You are fully funded for the year. And you can find a job in 5 minutes. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about money until 2022.
Be Of Service Seek opportunities for activities and projects that directly impact other people&amp;rsquo;s lives.
Working on a project/startup that build tools or platforms to do future good does not count.</description></item><item><title>Junk Media Diet</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2020-11-30-junk-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2020-11-30-junk-media-diet/</guid><description>Consuming news through Facebook, Reddit is the brain equivalent of eating McDonalds everyday.
Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong I love Reddit. But I hate the Reddit News tab. It sucks time and life away from me. And correcting this habit is as hard as turning one&amp;rsquo;s diet from burgers and chips to salad and pork chops.
I need to stay informed as much as I need to eat. I got my diet under control after years of learning.</description></item><item><title>Living Out Loud</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2020-11-08-lol/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2020-11-08-lol/</guid><description>I saw something interesting while browsing a very well organized collaborative Discord server.
It was a group of channels called Working out Loud. Each channel bears the name of a person, and it&amp;rsquo;s their &amp;ldquo;personal space&amp;rdquo;. Their office.
Most people were using this as a work log. For things like bookmarks, findings, status updates, etc. But of course also funny finds, rants, and conversation with people that &amp;ldquo;stop by the office&amp;rdquo; this way.</description></item><item><title>Karma</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2020-10-31-karma/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2020-10-31-karma/</guid><description>A few years ago I started to believe in Karma.
It confused me at first because from analytical perspective it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense.
I&amp;rsquo;ve seen things that seem too incredible to be explained. And it became more and more eerie as I figured out the general pattern. Or met other people that were aware of the same mechanisms.
It feels like a hack in the fabric of the universe. You just locally tweak a few variables in your local strategy, and suddenly the whole world unwinds in front of you.</description></item><item><title>Notes on GitHub</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2020-10-27-my-notes-on-github/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2020-10-27-my-notes-on-github/</guid><description>Can&amp;rsquo;t think of a good reason not to.
As long as I&amp;rsquo;m careful about not sharing something I later regret. 😬
Seems like a good way to establish a presence, build cred, and seed a public PURDAH.</description></item></channel></rss>