<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>📓 Marco's Notes</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/</link><description>Recent changes in 📓 Marco's Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright><atom:link href="https://notes.mpri.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>6 Months Freelancing</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2022-07-07-free-lancing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2022-07-07-free-lancing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Six months have passed since I went all-in on working as a freelance. The plan is to give it a shot for at least one year, and see how it goes. This halfway point seems like a good time to look back and reflect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mood-wise, I have been feeling content and satisfied. I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling fortunate and grateful for the situation I&amp;rsquo;m in. I choose my hours, employer, and schedule. Despite me being choosy, there&amp;rsquo;s still more work than I can ever take on. It feels nice to be wanted, professionally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Going back to a (mostly) regular schedule, had a positive effect on my mood. Last year I had no structure; every moment was a decision on how to spend the next chunk of time. Now I&amp;rsquo;m busy, and I had to give up some things I liked, but I&amp;rsquo;m happier overall. While the schedule is predictable, work and projects are not. Almost every day I am doing something new and different. And learning a lot, which gives me the greatest sense of accomplishment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Working hourly was an adjustment, and the first few months were stressful. I would count the minutes spent grocery shopping or washing dishes, and convert them into dollars lost. Going to the store is costing me $x, walking the dogs is costing me $y, and don&amp;rsquo;t get me started on vacations! This naggy voice gradually disappeared. I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped counting the minutes. Everything is fine. At the end of the month, I&amp;rsquo;ll still put in my hours and make enough money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking of money, the self-employment tax is a b***c! Most of what I have made this year, I will have to turn over in taxes. But it&amp;rsquo;s ok. I&amp;rsquo;m learning and growing. I knew leaving Big Tech would be a would be a significant income setback. I&amp;rsquo;ll make more money next year. And even a junior-like salary as Software Engineer is nothing to complain about!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over these six months, I have been working primarily with one company, on a series of related projects. I like this kind of long-term engagement. Altough sometimes I wonder if I should just join said company. I like them a lot, and love their product. But then I remember I much I love spending 100% of my work time doing&amp;hellip; work! No meetings, no email discussions, no chat notifications, no late-night sprints. I have a specific task, and when the clock is on, I feel the duty to be all-in. That makes it easier to be laser-focused and productive, which makes time fly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to the long-term (part-time) engagement, I have been involved in two more projects. They were interesting and rewarding. However, going forward, I will think twice about taking on multiple contracts at the same time. The context switch was tough, and I felt I was cheating on both projects by temporarily ignoring one to work on the other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ideally, I would like one contract that pays the bills, probably selling my more marketable skills. And then, in addition, a different amusing project. Eeither something of my invention OR learning a skill I find very useful and/or gripping. My objective for the reminder of this year, is to keep making progress toward this ideal situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I read somewhere &amp;ldquo;you can&amp;rsquo;t research and build at the same time&amp;rdquo;. It always sounded true. 2021 was all about research and exploration, and I was having a hard time producing anything of substance. Exploring was so enjoyable I was worried I would miss it after going back to work. But after six months with my head down working, it turns out I don&amp;rsquo;t. I still have time to chase the occasional rabbit down a hole. But most of the time I&amp;rsquo;m either building or learning or both. And it feels great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall: no regrets, full steam ahead. Slightly preoccupied, but that&amp;rsquo;s my natural state.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Waters</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2022-01-18-deep-waters/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2022-01-18-deep-waters/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This entry is an exercise in clarifying my goals for the year and the longer-term trajectory for my career. If you are reading this, keep in mind I am writing for myself. Publishing the result helps me keep myself accountable.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>At the start of my sabbatical year, I made a public declaration of my intentions for the year. In retrospect, I am really glad I did!
Those goals served as a guiding light throughout the year, when facing choices like &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>should I learn _?&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; Or &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>should I start project _?&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;.
They gave me focus, removed some options, and decreased the amount of self-doubt (&amp;quot;&lt;em>Is _ a waste of time? No. Practicing this is one of the objectives of the year!&lt;/em>&amp;quot;).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2021 has been a year-long experiment in working for myself.
I quite a few doubts at the start of the year:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Will I find work as a free agent?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Will I enjoy working for myself / by myself?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Can I be happier with less money?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>After a year of experimentation the answer is a resounding yes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I enjoy having a diverse set of opportunities available.
I enjoy creating my own mixture of multiple involvements, roles, projects.
I enjoy having more control over my schedule, more freedom to set direction and proceed as I see fit, on my own path.
Strangely enough, I enjoy making less money, because every dollar it&amp;rsquo;s more valuable, and I enjoy it more!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The path ahead of me is clear: I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go back to being an employee for now.
The 10 years in big tech were great, but I want the next 10 years to be different.
(Credit where it&amp;rsquo;s due: I am where I am with the luxury of a career change, thanks to those 10 years in Silicon Valley).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So why leave the safe harbor of Silicon Valley, the home of my industry?
In 2021, I got a taste of leaving the shore and exploring some open waters.
2022 is the year I start venturing out in deep, blue waters on my own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m scared of going off on my own like I&amp;rsquo;m scared to jump into deep seawater.
I know it&amp;rsquo;s mostly irrational, but it&amp;rsquo;s very real.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just need to jump in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are my guiding principles for the year 2022.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="stop">Stop&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="-worrying-about-money">&amp;hellip; worrying about money&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I am very lucky, my craft is in demand. Work opportunities are plenty, and they pay well. If ever need work, I will find some in about 5 minutes.
I can afford to be picky, even if choose contracts and projects based on personal preference rather than salary, I will still make good money.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="-being-a-small-cog-in-a-giant-machine">&amp;hellip; being a small cog in a giant machine&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>For years, it felt great to contribute (in small part) to world-renown products. But lately, the magic was gone, it just felt like I was helping a giant corporation become even more gigantic.
On the other side, seeing my little tacky projects and experiments used and appreciated has made me truly happy.
I should optimize for happiness, get better at building small cute things end-to-end.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="-trying-to-start-a-big-project">&amp;hellip; trying to start a big project&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I tried for all of 2021 to start a serious/large project, from my rotating wishlist of projects. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t.
While working for others as a freelance is easy, working truly for myself is hard.
Something is amiss, I haven&amp;rsquo;t quite figured myself out, but it&amp;rsquo;s not going to happen overnight. Let&amp;rsquo;s pause this for this year.
In 2022, focus on doing a good job with the existing commitments. They are diverse and interesting. I will learn a great deal. Only little and toy projects allowed, and hackathons.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="continue">Continue&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="-balancing-of-work-and-play">&amp;hellip; Balancing of work and play&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t miss being &amp;lsquo;on the clock&amp;rsquo; 9-5 Monday to Friday. However, the upside of that was a well-defined boundary between work and not work.
Today that line blurry. Gradually I found a new equilibrium where I can work more or less when I feel like it. It is way more than 40 hours a week, but almost all of it is enjoyable because I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em>choosing&lt;/em> to work.
I have the freedom to spend time with family and friends whenever I feel like it. The non-working hours give me the energy and desire to be more effective during working hours.
I should continue liberally allocating time (both planned and unplanned) to enjoy life, whatever that means in context.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="-making-space-for-serendipity">&amp;hellip; Making space for serendipity&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Consistently, the moments where I was further away and disconnected from my computer, were the moments that yielded the most light-bulb ideas, the most profound realizations, the most surprising ah-ah moments.
Similarly, exploration in the digital world &amp;ndash; going down rabbit holes not immediately related to my projects &amp;ndash; yielded invaluable treasures.
I should continue giving myself the freedom to be fully present in the moment, and explore serendipitously.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="-building-my-social-network">&amp;hellip; Building my social network&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In 2021, I&amp;rsquo;ve had 1:1 over 100 virtual meetings with people I had never met before. It takes work, energy, time to make these encounters happen. And it&amp;rsquo;s absolutely worth it.
100 out of 100 were inspiring and positive, 100 out of 100 made me walk away feeling enriched, inspired, or learned.
I should continue setting up impromptu meetings with people I find interesting, whenever there&amp;rsquo;s a good occasion.
Continue with a balance of new internet friends, and old IRL friends.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="start">Start&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="-being-more-selective-with-my-involvement">&amp;hellip; Being more selective with my involvement&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I ended 2021 oversubscribed on projects/collaborations/engagements. Biting more than I can chew is not good for anyone. Stress reduces my efficacy, and sooner or later I need to drop something.
I should start being more selective, keep a clear list of active projects, and not add anything willy-nilly. I need to start passing up on more opportunities and being ok with it. Don&amp;rsquo;t let FOMO make edits to the list.
A corollary is: be honest and clear with yourself and with others regarding how much time you can dedicate to something.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="-better-define-priorities">&amp;hellip; Better define priorities&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I often feel like I spent too much time on something that was not important at all. Often is due to detours, yak shaving, procrastination, distractions.
I think the first step is better priorities: recognizing that something is not worth the time I&amp;rsquo;m giving to it.
I want to get better at prioritizing and planning so that fewer hours are wasted.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="other-goals">Other goals&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Things I&amp;rsquo;d like to level up over the next year.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="skill-graphical-interfaces-front-end-development">Skill: graphical interfaces, front-end development&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In ~20 programming, I have almost zero experience with front-end and user interfaces. This holds me back: the only thing I can make are for other developers (libraries, APIs, infrastructure, &amp;hellip;).
Going forward, I want to build things usable and useful to a wider set of people, not just developers. To do this, I need to start learning some UI tools, technologies, and methods.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="skill-non-computer">Skill: non-computer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In large teams, specialization and deep narrow focus is a strength.
But out here, I&amp;rsquo;d like to level up a broad set of skills I&amp;rsquo;ve never really used before. Such as:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>User experience &amp;amp; design&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Research, marketing, advertisement, sales&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Project management&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Communication, writing for me and for others, mind-mapping, zooming&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Entrepreneurship&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="skill-scrappy-development-and-hacking">Skill: Scrappy development and Hacking&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In large-scale systems and infrastructure, a technical mistake can cost the company millions of dollars per hour. Every decision has ramifications, dependencies, side effects. Issues are multi-dimensional, and tradeoffs are non-linear. So for 10+ years I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to tread carefully.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the kind of project I work on these days, the result is I think too much before doing. This kills scrappy projects and ideas because I get stuck in the overthinking phase.
I am gradually becoming more effective at hacking things together. I am having a great deal of fun, and falling back in love with programming.
More small/just-for-fun/throwaway/fun projects are the key to getting better at this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>p.s. the same applies to writing &amp;ndash; way too much editorializing, where I should just throw down whatever comes to mind, then make it better iteratively, or next time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="skill-deep-focus">Skill: Deep focus&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten better at working in full focus on a particular task (a.k.a. being in the zone, flow state, etc). I could do better: getting there sooner, staying there longer, or more reliably, giving focus to diverse projects, etc.
I should keep observing what works, and try things to make it better.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="goal-find-a-technical-mentor">Goal: Find a technical mentor&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Good mentoring is equally valuable to both people.
I would like to find a mentor willing and happy to spend time with me regularly (even if it&amp;rsquo;s just for an hour a month).
Who am I looking for? 20+ years of industry experience, ranging from employee to funder. Background in systems engineering (or digital art, architect, applied scientist).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="other-principles">Other principles&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="invest-in-learning">Invest in learning&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Even if the subject is not of direct practical use. If you have the interest/energy to learn about something, go for it!
In practice: take online classes on things you don&amp;rsquo;t know, read books you normally wouldn&amp;rsquo;t, go to conferences and meetups.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="prioritize-good-for-the-world-over-profitable-for-me">Prioritize good for the world over profitable for me&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This goes by many names like (golden rule, karma, &amp;hellip;), and it is the base for any decision.
Focus on helping others with pure intentions, this makes the path ahead clear, full of joy and treasures.
The &amp;lsquo;pure&amp;rsquo; bit is important. I should be vigilant and recognize if my intentions are less than pure. If this is a transaction and not a gift, be honest and transparent about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="look-ahead">Look ahead&lt;/h3>
&lt;h5 id="3-year-target">3-year target&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Contribute to a few projects that benefit society and the planet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Live comfortably while working on projects that I find fun, interesting and that teach me valuable skills&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contribute to retirement funds&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="5-years-target">5-years target&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Bootstrap a personal project that outlives my involvement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Participate as key advisor/architect/contributor to the design and launch of a product&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contribute sizable amounts to charities, open-source, young people with ideas&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="10-years-target">10-years target&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Create a company based on an open-source project I started or adopted&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>2021 Recap</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-12-31-year-recap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-12-31-year-recap/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A worthy goal for a year is to learn enough about a subject so that you can’t believe how ignorant you were a year earlier &amp;ndash; &lt;a href="https://kk.org/thetechnium/68-bits-of-unsolicited-advice/">Kevin Kelly&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>As my sabbatical year comes to an end, I find myself asking: did i waste this year chasing butterflies, and being lazy? Or I did exactly what I was supposed to do, explore, experience, expand?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most days, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty confident it&amp;rsquo;s the latter. The year was incredibly enriching.
In an attempt to finally and definitively prove to my self I wasn&amp;rsquo;t just wasting time, I started compiling a list of all the awesome things I could remember.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I kept my 9-5 job, my bank account would be happier, but I would not have most of the things on this list (to be fair, this year was possible only thank to my 9-5 jobs I held for the previous 10 years).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>N.B. A link or mention is &lt;strong>not a endorsement&lt;/strong> of a project. It just means it was a positive experience for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="quests-adventures--experiences">Quests, Adventures &amp;amp; Experiences&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Talking to dozens of activists and hacktivists all over the world&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 talks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 social game/tools adopted by online communities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Hackaton prize&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A grant application&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Passing the Google interview&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Getting to know my extended family&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Consultations and freelance work&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moving to a new place&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rediscovering the joy of hacking and coding for fun&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sailing in the Bay&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 weeks in Italy (with incursions in France, Switzerland, Croatia)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A month in Brooklyn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lunch with DS, JM, &amp;amp; Prof. ML&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hugspocalypse&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://joinseeds.com/">SEEDS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://metagame.wtf/">MetaGame&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://raidguild.org/">RaidGuild&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.php.com/">Parents Helping Parents&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://imentor.org/">iMentor&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://equalit.ie/">Equalit.ie&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://synadia.com/">Synadia&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://kernel.community/">Kernel&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ethereum, web3, NFTs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moontribe&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills-acquired-andor-leveled-up">Skills (acquired and/or leveled up)&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="personal">Personal&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Communication and writing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Car buying/selling&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Home maintenance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open Source Software funding&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spells&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hourly work, time-management, planning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tame the nicotine monster&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Journaling, mind-mapping&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Entrepreneurship&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Personal finance&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="technical">Technical&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Golang&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Python (async, threads, data processing and visualization)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Discord bot APIs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Web hosting, static website generators, email hosting, DNS configuration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Self-hosted services, groupware&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Javascript&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Service design&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Vultr, Fly.io, AWS&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="tools">Tools&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Timers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://nats.io/">NATS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://nixos.org/">nix&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tmux">tmux&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://borgbackup.readthedocs.io/">borg&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://matrix.org/">Matrix&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://joinmastodon.org/">Mastodon&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.holochain.org/">Holochain&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://git-annex.branchable.com/">git-annex&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Docker&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="artifacts">Artifacts&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.mpri.me/skills">Skill Tree&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/MetaFam/skill-bot">skill-bot&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.mpri.me/">New homepage&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://notes.mpri.me/">Public notes and bookmarks&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.organic-social.net/">Organic Social&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spiral&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The first dollar earned as free agent&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Obsidian Rolodex&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="sources-of-wisdom-and-inspiration">Sources of wisdom and inspiration&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/">LessWrong&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/">HackerNews&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.atlasobscura.com/places/wonderville">Wonderville&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/user/1167593507">Le Papillon&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://nixnet.services">NixNet&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://darknetdiaries.com/">Darknet Diaries&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://xn--gckvb8fzb.com/superhighway84/">Superhighway84&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/s/qRxTKm7DAftSuTGvj">Hammertime&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://charleseisenstein.org/books/the-more-beautiful-world-our-hearts-know-is-possible/">The More Beautiful World Our Hearts Know Is Possible&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://kk.org/thetechnium/68-bits-of-unsolicited-advice/">https://kk.org/thetechnium/68-bits-of-unsolicited-advice/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Night_Circus">The Night Circus&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Interface (Neal Stephenson)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://fs.blog/tgmm/">Farnam Street&amp;rsquo;s Mental Models&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://thecrashcourse.com/topic/philosophy">Crash Course Philosophy&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://explorabl.es/">Explorabl.es&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://ncase.me/">Nicky Case&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regenerative_design">Regenerative Design&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nonviolent_Communication">Nonviolent Communication&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Permaculture">Permaculture&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Second Brain tools &amp;amp; Techniques&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Effective_altruism">Effective Altruism&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.hope.net/">Hackers of Planet Earth&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="new-and-old-friends">New and old friends&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>BC, PS, JH, DS ~
Pe, Mi, Pe, Gn ~
MG ~
MG, TK ~
MH &amp;amp; KM, Dr. RC ~
JJ, AS ~
AP ~
NH ~
PM ~
DC ~
MK, GB, SC ~
KY &amp;amp; WL ~
M ~
JG &amp;amp; GB ~
C&amp;amp;M ~
AS &amp;amp; CT&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Just Build</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-07-05-build/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-07-05-build/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the last 6 months, the prime directive has been to explore. To boldly go where I&amp;rsquo;ve never been before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve chased all sorts of opportunities and ideas while fighting back the instincts telling me that such projects are dead ends, not feasible long term, not sustainable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of fun overall, and now that I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to suppress my inner voices of doubt, it is even more rewarding and enjoyable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it is probably time for a change. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to get too comfortable.
The 6-months mark seems like a good time to draw a line and set a new heading.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the next 6 months I&amp;rsquo;d like to &lt;strong>build&lt;/strong> something.
No more micro-projects and fun adventures.
I&amp;rsquo;m ready for something big and complicated that will take hundreds of hours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am still going to ignore the financial angle and focus on project I love for one reason or another.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the past months, I have not been able to really dig too deep into any of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve had.
Too many other shiny things going by all day. Too many butterflies to chase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve read on some article I can&amp;rsquo;t recall: &amp;ldquo;Building while doing research is a fool&amp;rsquo;s errand. Do your research, then put your head down and build&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This rings true and relevant.
My current environment gives me 10 great ideas a day.
And that&amp;rsquo;s both a blessing and a curse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s time to end the expore and research phase, and start building.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the last month I tried something new inspired by &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/AndreasKling/videos">Andreas Kling&lt;/a>: Routine and habits are stronger than willpower.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve already unknowingly experienced and taken advantage of this.
For example: I workout every morning. It&amp;rsquo;s not because of the strength of my resolve. It&amp;rsquo;s because working out is deeply embedded in my routine.
If I don&amp;rsquo;t do it, I feel guilty and miserable. It&amp;rsquo;s automatic, I don&amp;rsquo;t need to think about it.
In other words, I am addicted to working out first thing in the morning (and that&amp;rsquo;s a great thing).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the last month, I&amp;rsquo;ve applied this mentality to a personal project that had been sitting in my list.
I allocated 30 minutes a day to this activity.
It worked out great!
Even if the project is very low on my list of priorities, I ended up working on it 20+ hours, and I enjoyed every minute of it.
The project looks great, and gets better every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Getting the ball rolling on a project has been difficult in the past.
The bigger the project, the harder it is to get going (duh, inertia!).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I intend do narrow down to 3 projects. Then dedicate one full day a week to each project for 3 months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 3 months, I should have something to show.
At the very least I hope to be &lt;em>moving&lt;/em> on all 3 projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To be honest, 3 seems too much. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid with everything else going on in parallel, my focus will be too diluted.
But as of now, I&amp;rsquo;m not able to let go of more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>6 Months Free-Wheeling</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-06-01-free-wheeling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-06-01-free-wheeling/</guid><description>&lt;p>The roller coaster of emotions has smoothed significantly.
Fear and anxiety have given way to joy and optimism.
I’m feeling grateful every day about the general state of affair and almost never regretting my choices or use of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Work opportunities have been coming from all direction.
And sharing my thoughts/ideas/projects with others consistently produces good feedback.
Both factors contribute to silencing the voices of doubt that were annoying me in the previous months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve gradually become less structured and learned to relax the self-inflicted micromanagement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve added a good amount of negative space in my schedule: time during which I’m distracted, having fun, or just not working on anything in particular.
During these times I’ve experienced the most fruitful breakthroughs and the most crystalline moments of clarity, unexpected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One problem still remains: too many opportunities and ideas, not enough time.
I’m more accepting of this condition. It’s now a source of wonder and happiness, rather than a source of anxiety.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m going to keep the weekly structure that worked well so far. But switch to planning from a simple single list of everything on my plate, roughly prioritized.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another great source of clarity and turning points have been conversations. The serendipitous ones, the regularly scheduled ones and the intentional ones, and the ones intentionally out there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would like to find a mentor and I would like to meet more potential collaborators with complementary missions and skills.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>March Madness</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-04-01-march-madness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-04-01-march-madness/</guid><description>&lt;p>The month of march begun with a feeling of being lost.
As more and more opportunities, projects, ideas started to materialize I found myself burning a lot of mental cycles thinking about time management. Questions such as:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How should I spend time?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Is this thing I&amp;rsquo;m doing a good use of my time?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Am I wasting my time?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;hellip;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The worst part of this is getting distracted by these questions and doubts.
They would constantly weight on my shoulder while working at something, and even more so during relax time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another thing I consistently find find myself asking is:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Am I doing this because I&amp;rsquo;m avoiding that?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Am I doing this because I find it pleasant, but it&amp;rsquo;s not worth the time in the long run?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Voicing these thoughts helped me come up with a plan to deal with this overhead and constant doubt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a first step, I&amp;rsquo;ve drawn a map of all the possible things I can do.
Then evaluated each one across different metrics: difficulty, personal interest, reason for consideration, potential payoff (monetary or otherwise).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Writing everything down helped it get it out of my head, which helped focusing on things I decided to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However the landscape is ever-changing, so I see myself doing this periodically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One surprising fact surfaced from the mapping exercise.
While bucketing the project based on &amp;ldquo;why am I thinking of working on this&amp;rdquo;, I realized one of the buckets was essentially the FOMO bucket: things I&amp;rsquo;m not necessarily passionate about but have great potential or opportunity.
Ignoring these ideas and projects feels wrong. It feels like leaving money on the table.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nevertheless, I resolved to avoid pursuing items in this bucket. My heart is not in it.
Someone else will do it, I wish them luck!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>March was a good month overall, I feel like I did quite a few things, and I don&amp;rsquo;t regret any of them.
Either I learned something, or made new friends, or inspired new ideas, or had fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among other things I earned my first ~dollar~ xDAI, which helps to tame the voice inside of me that worries about money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m liking the daily and weekly routine I&amp;rsquo;ve gradually switched to during the last month, described in the last post. I&amp;rsquo;ve added a day per week where I try to completely disconnect. Either by not opening my laptop at all, or by going somewhere that has no cellphone reception.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure what to do next, the landscape offers too many possibilities, and new ones come up everyday.
But at least I&amp;rsquo;m making progress building mental tools, processes and maps to deal with it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Clean Desk</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-02-25-clean-desk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-02-25-clean-desk/</guid><description>&lt;p>The first 6 weeks of 2021 have been a little rough.
I was spinning my wheels, I felt I was not accomplishing anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last couple of weeks have been great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M. mentioned how he cleans his desk when working on a particular thing.
My physical desk is always clean. But my virtual one wasn&amp;rsquo;t.
I was used to working with everything open: multiple messaging apps, multiple browsers with multiple tabs, multiple note-taking and TODO lists, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every alt-tab is a chance to get a glimpse of something that causes an interrupt and a heavy context switch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I started cleaning my desk and allocating time to work on just one thing.
And it&amp;rsquo;s fantastic. (Duh!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m also trying a new scheduling algorithm:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Morning&lt;/strong>: correspondence, one-off urgent small tasks, meetings&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Afternoon&lt;/strong>: single-task focus work (clean desk, everything closed and all notifications off)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Evening&lt;/strong>: reading, browsing, learning, small pleasant tasks&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do this Tue-Fri.
Monday is special and it&amp;rsquo;s reserved for big errands and tasks as well as planning small and big tasks for the rest of the week.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2021: The Plan</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-01-01-the-plan-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2021-01-01-the-plan-2021/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="forget-about-money">Forget About Money&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s no need to try to monetize your time or your projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worrying about money will only distract you and interfere with decision making.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You are fully funded for the year. And you can find a job in 5 minutes.
Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about money until 2022.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="be-of-service">Be Of Service&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Seek opportunities for activities and projects that &lt;strong>directly&lt;/strong> impact other people&amp;rsquo;s lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Working on a project/startup that build tools or platforms to do future good &lt;em>does not count&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As noble as it may sound, this does not &lt;strong>directly&lt;/strong> affect people&amp;rsquo;s lives.
That platform or tool may fail before it&amp;rsquo;s ever finished, or may never be adopted, or may end up doing more harm than good to society.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="local-over-global">Local Over Global&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s easier to &lt;strong>directly&lt;/strong> affect other people if you know them personally, or if at least you have a good understanding of their world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So start there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As much as I would like to help people in war-zone, or forests destroyed, or animal species going extinct&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t have a clue how to do it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So start with helping people around you.
Then take what you learn and broaden your scope (next year).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Acting local will also have ripple effect that are hard for me to comprehend.
Teaching a man to fish here today, may result in that man teaching other 100 tomorrow somewhere else.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dont-fight-uphill">Don&amp;rsquo;t Fight Uphill&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You may see a problem and &lt;em>know&lt;/em> you have the answer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet the people involved may reject your help or your solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t get stuck. If the terrain is not fertile, move on and find fertile ground!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="always-be-learning">Always Be Learning&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>No project is pointless and unsuccessful if you learned something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And learning something new should be sufficient reason to jump into a project.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="stand-still-sometimes">Stand Still, Sometimes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With the start of the year, I decided to leave behind a big chunk of my identity (i.e., my successful corporate tech career).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before a new story begins, there will be a period of emptiness.
This is sometimes referred to as &lt;em>winter&lt;/em> or &lt;em>death&lt;/em>, depending on context.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This period will feel uncomfortable. I will feel empty and worthless.
It&amp;rsquo;s a natural reaction to flail, run around, try everything to get out of this situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But running around may in fact dig me in even deeper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I need to embrace the discomfort. Only when I stop fighting it will be able to see a way out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>N.B&lt;/em> this post is backdated. While these thoughts were pretty clear to me by the end of 2020, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the clarity to write them down until February 2021.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Junk Media Diet</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2020-11-30-junk-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2020-11-30-junk-media-diet/</guid><description>&lt;p>Consuming news through Facebook, Reddit is the brain equivalent of eating McDonalds everyday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong I love Reddit.
But I hate the Reddit News tab. It sucks time and life away from me.
And correcting this habit is as hard as turning one&amp;rsquo;s diet from burgers and chips to salad and pork chops.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I need to stay informed as much as I need to eat.
I got my diet under control after years of learning. I eat plenty of amazing food and my belly is right where i want it.
I need to do the same for my brain food.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Social Media News needs to go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My main source of daily news is an aggregator [1].
I collected hundreds of amazing feeds of all kinds.
But I actually never read anything but the daily news.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If Social Media News is McDonalds, then Mass Media News (CNN, New York Times, Fox, &amp;hellip;) is frozen TV dinner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I try to keep it healthy by adding variety[2].
Seeing the same bit of news presented and dressed by different countries or by opposite sides of the political spectrum is great to get a tridimensional view of the actual events, their ramifications, and the landscape around them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In contrast, feeding exclusively on news from Facebook + Fox News, or on CNN + New York Times + Reddit is like eating the same frozen lasagna. Every. Single. Night.
If all you have is a freezer and a microwave. Let it it be frozen dinner. But at least add some variety.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe get together a bunch of sources.
For politics, left wing and right-wing. Centrist and extremist. Intellectual and clickbait-y.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to add more news from more places around the world and local/remote/global communities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The upside AND downside of multiple contrasting feeds is the redundancy of the information.
So maybe I could make diverse buckets for different days?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If treated as the occasional snack, I could still fit some Reddit in the mix.
Just stay TF out of the News tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rest of my mind diet is not too bad, but it could be better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Books are the brain equivalent to vegetables for the body. I believe in eating plenty.
I dedicate a fair amount of time to books, but I&amp;rsquo;m super slow, stopping to think every 5 minutes[3].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Podcasts and long-form conversation are the protein of my diet.
I&amp;rsquo;m mindful of where my protein comes from. I cook it myself. And and if I could, I would eat more.
Similarly, I wish i could consume more podcasts.
But what i listen to, doesn&amp;rsquo;t go bad. If I get to it in a year, it&amp;rsquo;s still going to be delicious brain food.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Too often if I go out for a run, I fall back to listening to current events.
So I love political satire is my bacon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then, there&amp;rsquo;s the good stuff.
Which I&amp;rsquo;m just starting to explore and discover.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reading a good article can be as joyful as eating a fresh oyster on a hot summer day.
A joy for the senses and wonderful fuel for the body.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just like my first time eating sashimi i was diffident, but I quicly learned to love it.
The same way I&amp;rsquo;m learning to love articles and thoughts from semi-anonymous internauts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s an world of delicious, homemade, ethically sourced, organic brain food out there that I cannot wait to explore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[1] I like Feedly, but I&amp;rsquo;ll probably switch to something else soon.
[2] Euronews or Al Jazeera. Daily Beast and Breitbart.
[3] Thinking back, I always loved manuals and technical books, and I always struggled with the long dense paragraphs, history for example.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Living Out Loud</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2020-11-08-lol/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/diary/2020-11-08-lol/</guid><description>&lt;p>I saw something interesting while browsing a very well organized collaborative Discord server.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was a group of channels called &lt;strong>Working out Loud&lt;/strong>.
Each channel bears the name of a person, and it&amp;rsquo;s their &amp;ldquo;personal space&amp;rdquo;. Their office.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most people were using this as a work &lt;em>log&lt;/em>.
For things like bookmarks, findings, status updates, etc.
But of course also funny finds, rants, and conversation with people that &amp;ldquo;stop by the office&amp;rdquo; this way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everyone can choose to follow this &lt;em>feeds&lt;/em> from collaborators.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the &lt;em>Working out Loud&lt;/em> meme is brilliant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I want to do on this repository is some version of &lt;strong>Live out Loud&lt;/strong> ([1]).
Browse out loud, learn out loud, think out loud.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is nothing new, Facebook and Instagram are &lt;em>Living out Loud&lt;/em> platforms too. And countless others before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Modern social media however, is very high throughput.
The platform feeds me updates continuously. And prods me to produce new ones for others to consume.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would like this sharing to be nothing like that.
I would like this to be slow and organic. Like growing a tree over the years.
And I would like it to be useful to present and future Internauts, as well as being a good representation of some sides of me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Earlier today, Seneca, provided some clarity:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You demand an account of my days - generally as well as
individually. You think well of me if you suppose that there is
nothing in them for me to hide. And we should, indeed, live
as if we were in public view, and think, too, as if someone
could peer into the inmost recesses of our hearts&amp;rsquo;- which
someone can! [2]&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I wonder who else out there is breaking out of the piecemeal content creation and doing something more similar to this. I should do some research.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>[1] Strictly limited to some dimensions on my life I&amp;rsquo;m willing to make public.
And &lt;em>especially&lt;/em> keeping into account the privacy of others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[2] Seneca - Epistnlae Morales ad Lucilium, Letter LXXXIII - &lt;a href="https://duckduckgo.com/?q=%27Letters+from+a+Stoic%27%2C+Robin+Campbell%27s+translation">&amp;lsquo;Letters from a Stoic&amp;rsquo;, translated by Robin Campbell&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>