<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Topics on 📓 Notes</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/</link><description>Recent content in Topics on 📓 Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://notes.mpri.me/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Mellow Introduction to the Blockchain Universe</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/blockchain-intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/blockchain-intro/</guid><description>A Mellow Introduction to the Blockchain Universe This presentation is open source (CC BY-NC-SA 4.0)
In 2020, I decided to quit my tech job to pursue other (tech) dreams.
Whenever someone asks me what I&amp;rsquo;m up to these days, the blockchain comes up.
Most people (both technical and not) at this point heard the term, but nobody is sure of exactly what the blockchain is.
This presentation is my best attempt at communicating what the big deal is, what is going on in the digital world, and what the future might bring.</description></item><item><title>Breaking into NFTs: A Guide for Artists</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/breaking-into-nfts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/breaking-into-nfts/</guid><description>This presentation is open source (CC BY-NC-SA 4.0)
Breaking into NFTs: A Guide for Artists Hello World! Thank you to the wonderful folks of ARTogether for organizing this event.
whoami Technology enthusiast, Distributed system engineer (I make lots of computers talk to each-other).
I have an affinity with blockchain due to academic research (10+ years ago). Consensus, the math underlying blockchain technology.
I have little interest in cryptocurrencies and NFTs.</description></item><item><title>Federated Architectures</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/federated-architectures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/federated-architectures/</guid><description>The recurring theme of federation in distributed system Some editorial choices about this deck:
Entertaining &amp;gt; Precise Cool &amp;gt; Useful Future &amp;gt; Present (Presenter notes available in the source of these slides)
IRL Federation United Federation of Planets 🖖 United States 🇺🇸 Most companies (teams, franchises, branches) 🏭 Federation: organization pattern involving a combination of centralized decision-making and as peripheral autonomy
Hybrid of top-down (hierarchical) and peer-to-peer (decentralized)</description></item><item><title>From Monopoly to Ouropoly</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/monopoly-ouropoly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/monopoly-ouropoly/</guid><description>MetaFest 2021 A short talk about Monopoly, Ouropoly, Blockchain, reunion, and the future.
This presentation is open source (CC BY-NC-SA 4.0)</description></item></channel></rss>