<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Topics on 📓 Notes</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/</link><description>Recent content in Topics on 📓 Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://notes.mpri.me/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Choosing Cloud Storage</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/cloud-storage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/cloud-storage/</guid><description>These days there are literally hundreds of options when it comes to choosing cloud storage.
Wether it&amp;rsquo;s for personal use, family sharing, for a small project or for a company.
Too many times, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen people draw a short list from household names (Dropbox, Amazon, BitTorrent, &amp;hellip;) and then narrow it down, primarily based on cost.
This list of questions is designed to make you stop and think a little more about what you are looking for.</description></item><item><title>Docker reference</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/docker/</guid><description>attach Attach local standard input, output, and error streams to a running container build Build an image from a Dockerfile commit Create a new image from a container's changes create Create a new container cp Copy files/folders between a container and the local filesystem diff Inspect changes to files or directories on a container's filesystem export Export a container's filesystem as a tar archive import Import the contents from a tarball to create a filesystem image history Show the history of an image save Save one or more images to a tar archive (streamed to STDOUT by default) update Update configuration of one or more containers tag Create a tag TARGET_IMAGE that refers to SOURCE_IMAGE load Load an image from a tar archive or STDIN images List images rmi Remove one or more images exec Run a command in a running container rm Remove one or more containers ps List containers run Run a command in a new container rename Rename a container login Log in to a Docker registry logout Log out from a Docker registry pull Pull an image or a repository from a registry push Push an image or a repository to a registry search Search the Docker Hub for images events Get real time events from the server top Display the running processes of a container port List port mappings or a specific mapping for the container stats Display a live stream of container(s) resource usage statistics logs Fetch the logs of a container kill Kill one or more running containers pause Pause all processes within one or more containers restart Restart one or more containers unpause Unpause all processes within one or more containers wait Block until one or more containers stop, then print their exit codes stop Stop one or more running containers start Start one or more stopped containers run: create a new container docker run -d -p X:Y &amp;lt;image&amp;gt; -d for detach -p to map port X of the host to port Y of the container Interactive shell New container:</description></item><item><title>Federated Architectures</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/federated-architectures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/federated-architectures/</guid><description>The recurring theme of federation in distributed system Some editorial choices about this deck:
Entertaining &amp;gt; Precise Cool &amp;gt; Useful Future &amp;gt; Present (Presenter notes available in the source of these slides)
IRL Federation United Federation of Planets 🖖 United States 🇺🇸 Most companies (teams, franchises, branches) 🏭 Federation: organization pattern involving a combination of centralized decision-making and as peripheral autonomy
Hybrid of top-down (hierarchical) and peer-to-peer (decentralized)</description></item><item><title>macOS startup service and daemons</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/macos-startup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/macos-startup/</guid><description>Reference to find and stop annoying applications and services that auto-start on login or auto-restart when killed.
launchd LaunchDaemon items run with system privileges LaunchAgent items run in user context after login launchd auto-loads from the following locations:
~/Library/LaunchAgent /Library/LaunchAgents /Library/LaunchDaemons /System/Library/LaunchAgents /System/Library/LaunchDaemons Notice that /System/ is protected by system integrity checks, so it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely that&amp;rsquo;s where apps registers.
List services: launchctl list
Dump launchd state: launchctl dumpstate</description></item><item><title>Personal document management with git</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/git-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/git-basics/</guid><description>This tutorial is for my dear friend M. Like any person working on computers, M. struggles with keeping track of changes to files.
This is the simplest possible tutorial that explains how to leverage git for very simple personal projects.
This tutorial covers:
Versioning of a small set of files for a single person. i.e. personal notes/essay/homeworks/article, &amp;hellip; Inspecting and restoring of old versions Backups and sharing with others via cloud This tutorial does NOT cover branching, stashes, resolving conflicts, merge strategies, rewriting history, pulling from remote, fixups, aliases, configuration, etc.</description></item><item><title>Smoking</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/smoking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/smoking/</guid><description>Some experiences and learning while trying to kick the habit.
Context: I&amp;rsquo;ve smoked since i was 16 or so. Successfully quit once, cold turkey, for about 4 years. Then picked it back up and have been smoking since, but also trying to stop since.
Cold Turkey My friend&amp;rsquo;s J&amp;rsquo;s father smoked 2 packs a day for as long as I&amp;rsquo;ve known him. One night he saw me smoking, pulled me aside, and told me he had quit.</description></item><item><title>tmux Reference</title><link>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/tmux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notes.mpri.me/topics/tmux/</guid><description>CLI tmux ls: List sessions
tmux a: Reattach last used
tmux a -t &amp;lt;session-name&amp;gt;: Reattach
tmux source-file ~/.tmux.conf: Reload
Commands Default prefix: Ctrl-b
?: List commands d: Detatch :list-keys :refresh-client :source-file ~/.tmux.conf Windows c: New window :new-window -n &amp;lt;name&amp;gt; &amp;lt;N&amp;gt;: Switch to window N w: Select p: Previous n: Next x: Kill ,: Rename Panes &amp;quot;: horizontal split %: vertical split &amp;lt;space&amp;gt;: rearrange o: focus next &amp;lt;arrow&amp;gt;: move focus ctrl-&amp;lt;arrow&amp;gt;: resize }: swap !</description></item></channel></rss>